Good morning. You're watching a special
edition of the program with Ted Roll and
John Kuryaku. It's Sunday, March 1st,
2026. Uh we are normally here Monday
through Friday, 9:00 am Eastern time on
YouTube and Rumble, but uh and streaming
whenever, but obviously with the news
out of the out of Iran and the Middle
East, um John and I decided we needed to
pipe in and uh say our peace and answer
questions and uh try to analyze things
as best we could. Thanks so much for
joining us, John.
>> Hey, good to see you, Ted. Glad to be
back even on a Sunday. And I want to say
too, forgive forgive my my video. I'm in
a hotel in Brooklyn. I have only my
phone, so I apologize for the quality of
my of my picture.
>> It's actually looks pretty good, John.
>> Oh, good, good, good. Okay.
>> And you sound good, too. It's a good
connection.
>> I'm gonna I'm gonna make this nicer.
Okay, there we go.
>> Great. All right. So, let me go over
some of the Obviously, today's uh we're
only going to be talking about Iran,
nothing else. uh even though there's
plenty else going on in the world. Um
basically uh yesterday the big news
being that uh Supreme Leader um Ali
Kamini was uh who's been leading Iran
for nearly 37 years was killed by an
Israeli air strike that was guided by
the United States. Um that was confirmed
by the Iranians. Um, the CIA apparently
told Trump before he decided to attack
Iran that there was a strong chance that
Kamini would probably be replaced by
someone who was at least as hardline as
he is. Maybe someone from the
revolutionary guards. An interim
council's been announced. Uh, Ayatollah,
a senior cleric named Ayatollah Ali
Arafi, sorry for the butchering of the
language there, has been announced.
We'll talk about that. Uh the New York
Times is reporting that basically
insiders are saying that the diplomacy
never had a chance due to the way that
the Trump administration was approaching
and talking to the Iranians and it may
have just all been misdirection all
along. Uh polls show that only 21% of
Americans support this war at its very
at its inception. I think that's insane.
I've never heard of anything like it.
Normally 21% is like after you've lost
the war and everyone's turned against it
and even then it doesn't get that bad. I
think more people supported the Vietnam
War in 1973 than than 21%. Um Trump is
hiding somewhere. We don't know where.
The no speeches to the nation. Um and uh
no no public no public uh statements. Um
oil futures, not surprisingly, are clo
are uh are soaring. We'll see what
happens when the markets open tomorrow,
but we'll know more when the Asian
markets open later today um due to the
time difference. Uh there's uh and of
key members of Congress are pushing for
a war powers resolution. Um mo notably
Roana Thomas Massie want a public vote.
Looks like they're probably going to get
one. Um and so this is a unique set of
circumstances. Uh the straight of Hormuz
um Iran claims has been closed by them.
Uh my favorite quote, John, was from
their social media feed where they said,
you know, we have blocked the straight
of Ormuz. Let the orange pig try to
unblock it.
>> Oh my god. Oh my god. I didn't see that.
>> So great.
>> I don't mean I don't mean to laugh, but
>> Well, you do have to laugh because war
does always have like some funny moments
like Baghdad Baghdad Bob. Um
>> Baghdad Bob. and and there's like and
and then there was also this really
weird moment yesterday at NBC News,
which used to be a news organization. Um
they they were interviewing an top
Iranian official and uh they said, "How
can you justify um hitting these
military b the US military bases?" And
he's like, "But that's the places that
are firing the weapons at us in the war
that you started." I mean, literally,
there's never there's no more
justifiable military action than that.
Um, I don't know. Very strange.
>> Unbelievable. Well, things are things
are bad, Ted. Bad all around. The I I
spoke to friends of mine in Kuwait, uh,
Gutter, and the United Arab Emirates
yesterday.
Um, it's funny the I talked to a a
guttery the son of a senior guttery
official yesterday and he just kind of
chuckled and said, "Well, this is life
in the Middle East. We live in a
dangerous neighborhood." My my friends
in Dubai were panicked. Uh, the Burj
Alab, the the giant ultralux hotel that
shaped like a sail.
Um, the Iranians fired or not fired but
sent a drone to to blow up on it. The
drone was intercepted and hit in the
air, but when it exploded, it exploded
against the hotel and set the hotel on
fire. The fire was put out, but there's
significant damage. The Iranians um sent
drones to attack the Burj Khalifa, the
tallest building in the world. They hit
it with two drones. Um maybe even more
importantly though, Manama airport in
Bahrain is unusable. It has to be closed
for a while and repaired. Kuwait
International Airport in Kuwait has
>> interruption, John, about the Bahraini
airport. There's reports that the
Bahraini local firefighting brigade
refused to put out the fire to fight
that fire. You know, I would actually
believe that because
Bahrain is a majority Shia Muslim
country just like Iran is Shia Muslim
and Bahrain has a Sunni Muslim royal
family which can be a problem at times.
Heads are going to roll if that's true,
but I it doesn't surprise me.
So anyway, the the the Iranians, you
know, the Iranians can't win this thing,
of course, but but they can put up a
fight and they can they can, you know,
put some hurt out on uh on the Gulf Arab
states
>> and they could survive, right? I mean,
that's what victory looks like for them.
Um yeah, I mean, this is a this is a
regime that's really built for survival.
It's been under siege since 1979.
Um the uh you know they they have as we
talked about yesterday in the other
extra edition that we did yesterday
morning um John there was a you know
there's there's redundant governmental
systems there. Um the they you know
these decapitation strikes certainly hit
hard. Um the Israelis and the Americans
killed a lot of top officials. But you
know they have a succession plan. They
have number twos number threes ready to
step in. They always did. They always
knew something like this could happen.
Um, I mean, it's I don't see how you
overthrow this regime
um this way, unless the Iranian people
rise up and overthrow it, but I don't
see how that happens,
>> which we're not seeing. So, I'm seeing
I'm seeing video from Iran. You know, on
CNN, they'll show you video from Iran.
It's like 300 people dancing and waving
and whatever, beeping their horns. But
then you see video of a million people
out in the street self flagagillating
and crying and vowing to fight the west
to the death.
Think of it this way too.
A peaceful transition of power from the
current regime to some substitute regime
is in US interests. Chaos and death is
what is in Israel's interests
>> and that's what we're more likely to
get.
>> And that's what we're more we're more
likely to get.
>> I think Netanyahu is hoping for a civil
war.
>> I think that's exactly what the plan is.
Yes.
>> Yeah. Um okay. So let's uh should we go
to the questions because there's a lot
of in the
all that. So, as usual, uh if you're
watching live, please put your question
at this point uh into the Rumble and the
YouTube chat and producer Robbie will uh
get will let us know what you have to
say and we will answer. And before we
before we do the first question, Robbie
um Robbie's reading, you know, these
these live updates on Telegram and there
are reports, we don't know if they're
true yet, but there are reports that the
USS Abraham Lincoln is under attack,
which is exactly what we said we feared
last week. If you send enough drones or
a hypersonic missile against an aircraft
carrier, you can't defend it. So waiting
to see how that plays out.
>> And okay, well we have some record U.
Robbie says he has some housekeeping to
do. So let's put him on.
>> Yeah, just real quick because it's such
a busy day. Uh later today, I do not
know when because things are just really
hectic right now. Naturally, I will be
launching John's official TikTok. Will
that happens? I will post a link on his
ex account so you'll be able to actually
follow the real John Keryaku. Uh John
also has a real account on Rumble. If
you go to rumble.comcjuryaku
official, that is his official channel.
His stuff will be going up today,
including shorts. And I'll also be
working on doing the same thing for your
favorite cartoonist, Ted R, at a later
time, but it will be this month. Uh last
little thing, if you're in the chat, if
you're a dick, I will ban you. Don't do
it. I You can ask questions. You can be
snarky, but if you're an [__] I will
bury you. So, don't do it.
Thank you, Robbie. Okay. Um, let's do um
let's do
>> I lost your uh lost your your uh
microphone, Ted.
>> Oh, really?
>> Can't hear you.
>> You can't hear me? I hear you.
>> Can't hear you. Robbie, can you hear
Ted?
>> I hear you.
>> Then maybe it's me.
>> Try jumping out real quick, John. Then
jumping back in. Sometimes phones will
act crazy.
Okay. So, let's see what happens here.
Um, so all right. So, yeah, Robbie, um,
any news? Any more news on the Abraham
Lincoln? No.
>> Uh, nothing new from what I shared just
before we went live.
>> Okay, we're waiting for John to pipe
back in here. Uh, okay. There he is.
All right, John. Do you hear us?
>> There we go. That That works. Okay.
>> Okay. Good. Cool. Cool. All right,
Robbie. Thank you for that. Um, all
right. So, shall we do a ready for some
questions?
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Hello, heroes. Thank you. Do
you think any of the Arab countries that
were struck will actually strike back or
will they count on the US and Israel to
do this for them? I'm wondering uh the
cultural dynamics playing into this
decision like losing face, appearing
weak, or being peaceful during Ramadan.
The Ramadan thing is interesting to me,
too. Yeah, this is a big sin for this to
be launched during Ramadan.
>> Um, my UAE contacts told me yesterday
that um, they sent their ships out of
port not to fight, but just to protect
them. Uh, we have not seen retaliation
uh, from the Arab states yet. And my
guess is we probably won't. that they're
gonna let the US and Israel do their
thing with some British air cover and
that's gonna be it.
>> I agree with that completely. Uh Donkey
Man, do we think that war will last more
than a month? I think it will.
>> Yeah, you know, that's a great question.
Donald Trump said yesterday it's only
going to last a couple of days. He lives
in a fantasy world if he thinks this is
going to last a couple of days. Um, I
wouldn't be surprised if there are
active US and Israeli hostilities for
weeks, but yeah, I could see this
lasting for a month. Sure.
>> I mean, especially if um the Iranians
bloody the Israelis or our noses in some
way that we can't fathom, right? They
get a missile gets through and I don't
know, blows up something that Israel or
we care about a lot and it and then
there's a domest there's, you know, a
domestic concern that we can't just let
it go.
That's right.
>> Okay. Um, let's uh, is Iran actually
causing damage anywhere? Even with the
numerous missiles fired, it doesn't seem
to do much. Is Iran hoping for an
off-ramp hope still? Oh, I'm sure
they're hoping for an off-ramp. The
Israelis killed practically everybody.
It's not just the Ayatollah, his
daughter, son-in-law, and grandson. It's
it's the entire Iranian military
leadership was wiped out yesterday.
Yeah. So the second and third string
guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Yeah. No. I mean, so but is Iran
actually causing any damage anywhere is
the question.
>> Oh,
not that I've seen. I mean, sure. Yeah.
I mean, they they fired rockets at Jebel
Ali, the uh the the free port in Dubai.
They they have they've damaged Manama
and Kuwait airports. Uh they fired a
rocket at the Saudi oil fields that was
intercepted. A couple of hotels were
were damaged in Dubai.
>> Yeah. One rocket landed in Abu Dhabi.
There's some damage, but absolutely
nothing like what's being inflicted on
Iran.
>> No, no, no question. It's definitely a
one-way street there when it comes to
that. Um but all they have to do is
survive. Um, Diva Divvia, do we think
hitting Dubai hard would be beneficial
for Iran right now because of all the
American interests right now?
>> Uh, I think no. And I'll tell you why.
Because that's where Iran does its
business. Iran I mean Dubai is chock
full of Iranian businessmen and that's
Iran's outlet to the Western world.
That's how Iran evades sanctions by
having businesses in Dubai. So, I think
no, hitting Dubai is not going to help
Iran at all.
>> John, during um during the uh Iraq war,
Bush and Cheney, especially the latter,
kept saying, "Oh, we're going to have
cheap oil because of this." Um turned
out it went exactly the opposite way. Um
I I think I see a replay here. I think
the real damage is going to be economic.
I mean, high oil prices means high
everything prices. This is a president
who's trying to fight inflation more
than anything else, right? I mean,
that's the real risk to him. That's
right. That's exactly right. And it's
not like Venezuelan oil is a panacea.
It's not. It's filthy. It's heavy. You
have to inject it with massive amounts
of chemicals to clean it up just to make
it into home heating oil. So, Venezuela
is not going to be the answer to our
prayers. Oil prices are going to go up.
>> Uh, Sassan, we get such great questions.
Um, thank you. You guys are great. Um,
what do you think is the impact of the
death of Kami on the uh future of the
regime in Iran? As an Iranian, I'm
worried yet another extremist is chosen
and the cycle continues on and on. Love
the show. That I think is exactly what's
going to happen.
>> Absolutely 100% agree. That is exactly
what's going to happen. You know, and
the thing too is that
I think that in the west we seriously
overestimated Ayatollah Kamay's
authority. Mhm.
>> Certainly he was the final word on on
religious issues. Certainly. But you can
take him out and have literally nothing
change.
>> It's like if you killed the pope.
>> Yes. Exactly. Exactly.
>> No.
>> No. That's wonderful. I'm gonna I'm
going to repeat that.
>> Uh M. Uh oh. Uh let's see. Reload. Um
please reload. What are you doing? Okay.
Good morning, gentlemen. the sneaky part
of my brain wondered how much of a
beating Iran will suffer be before
finally unleashing their hypersonic
missiles. I think they proved during
their probing strike on Iron Dome that
letting Israel and the US burn through
their limited arms supply that patience
is the best practice. Yeah. I mean, you
learned that when you have 7,000 years
of continuous culture, right? Also, why
does the American government always
imagine that killing a leader will end a
war?
>> I know, right?
>> Ted, you mentioned the time frame
Germany fought beyond Hitler. If Trump
was killed today, nothing about our
country's day-to-day would change. And
somehow and somehow we expect other
countries to be different.
>> It's it's it's a childish mentality.
>> The New York Times just issued a push
notification saying that the Iranian
foreign minister says that a new Supreme
Leader will be chosen in the next day or
two. So there it is right there. Nothing
changes. It you can take out the Pope
and there's just going to be another
pope.
>> Yeah. If you and I were in the Iranian
leadership or any leadership that was
besieged like this, we would say, "Oh,
we have to project continuity uh in
order to maintain domestic control. I
mean, they don't like the fact that
there have been protests and even if it
is just 300 people, you know, going
they don't like that. That's 300 too
many." Um, you know, regimes radicalize
under in times of war. That's
>> Yes, they do.
>> You know, that's just sort of history.
Um, you know, hypersonic missiles, but
we got, you know,
Are do they exist? Are they real?
>> Oh, yeah. They're real. The Russians
have them. The Chinese have them. The
Iranians have them.
>> The Iranians have them. That's what I
mean. Iranians have them exist.
>> So So they're So they're they're so the
Iranians keep are, you know, using their
usual FID language um as as they do to
say like today is going to be we're
going to unleash our doomsday scenario.
Okay. Maybe. But
>> yeah. No, but the the danger of
hypersonic missiles is they'll go three
or four times the speed of sound. So
you're you're dealing with a missile
going 2500 miles an hour. You can't
defend against a missile going 2500
miles an hour. And so maybe you can get
it into, you know, the Knesset building
or you can get it into the side of the
USS Abraham Lincoln or something like
that. And then, you know, the West is
going to have to deal with it. They
don't have a lot of them. They only have
a couple of them, but you know, we'll
see if they find them.
>> It's like the Afghan mujaheden in the
80s, right? They didn't have that many
stingers. They had to make count.
>> That's right. And they did.
>> Um, hello gentlemen, big fan. Wondering
if you think Iran's sleeper cells, if
they have, will be activated and if they
will be activated in the UK. In
addition, what will China's likely
response be? John, where do you get
those lovely sweaters like you wore on
Diary of a CEO from?
Let's dispose of the sleeper cells. Um
they're probably they don't exist,
right?
>> Um I don't think they exist in the US,
Canada,
>> maybe.
>> Probably the UK probably, but they
certainly exist in places like Pakistan,
India, Indonesia. Yeah, they're out
there. They're out there. Um and thank
you for that. I I get these sweaters at
at Macy's.
>> Oh, really? I thought you brought them
back from Greece or something. Uh okay.
China's response. Well, we already China
is doing what they always do. Um,
they're trying to be the adults in the
room. They keep saying like, "You guys
stop respect Iran's sovereignty. Just
stop." But that I think it's going to be
that's going to be about it.
>> Ted, there was a headline on The Onion a
couple of weeks ago that was funny
because it was so true. And the headline
was China content to sit back and watch
US destroy itself.
>> And that's what we're going to see here.
>> No doubt. Um, how much leverage Jasper
wants to know, does this give countries
like Russia and China to pursue their
military goals such as in Taiwan? I I'm
not convinced that that that Ti China
wants to invade Taiwan. Uh,
>> no, I don't think so. If China wanted to
invade Taiwan, they would have done it
two days ago.
>> Yeah, that time
>> I I am I'm you and I, Ted, we're in the
minority of people who who believe that
China is not interested in invading
Taiwan. Yeah, we
>> and the Russians are very happy to see
us distracted in fighting the Iranians
so they can focus on the Ukrainians and
not have the American monkey on their
backs.
>> Yeah. No, I mean this this definitely
look uh you know when the cat's away
it's always a good time and we're the
cat. Um uh Matt, I can remember Bob Bear
writing ex extensively about the Iranian
threat, specifically the ability to
covertly retaliate against the West and
shut down the straight of Hormuz. Any
thoughts? It's been years since I read
his book, Memories Fazy, but
>> no, that that that memory is correct.
That's exactly what Bob Bear wrote
about. And uh and he was correct then.
When he wrote that book 25 years ago,
he's correct today. Um the Iranians can
shut the straight of Hormuz. If I were
the Iranian leader, I would shut the
straight of Hormuz. um they're not going
to they're not going to win a sustained
bombing campaign, but over the long
term, you know, they live there. It's
their neighborhood and they can inflict
real economic harm on the West.
>> Um Ted and John, thank Declan Brady. I
love the show. Welcome your unbiased
opinions and analysis. Why do you think
Iran is attacking its neighbors? Surely
as the agrieved party, Iran needs all
the support it can get. And how does
hitting Dubai and Kuwaiti airports help
their cause? Hope your comes through
John.
>> It's because there are there are two US
military bases in Kuwait. The
headquarters of the American fifth fleet
is in Bahrain. The world's largest US
air force base is in gutter. Two US Army
bases are in um the Emirates. Uh there
are multiple US military both army and
air force bases in Saudi Arabia. So
there's no love of Iran in these
countries. Well, exactly. I'm glad you
you said that there. I mean, I think I
think that's the final calculus, John.
These aren't their friends. They're not
going to get they're not going to become
friends. These are not any none of these
targeted countries are going to help the
Iranians in any way, shape, or form.
They're not even going to tweet on their
behalf.
>> Absolutely not.
>> Uh, as someone who served in the Ma
Navy, Amy, Andy wants to know, this is
very concerning for me. Do you think
we'll need to put boots on the ground
for this locally? That right there is
the $64,000 question.
>> So everybody at the White House, the
Pentagon, and the State Department, and
all the talking heads from Capitol Hill
say that there will be no boots on the
ground. That would be the death nail for
the United States if we were if we had
to put boots on the ground and fight a
country of 92 million people. You know,
I'm going to reiterate what you said
yesterday, Ted, and that is that the US
and Israel have to win. The Iranians
just have to survive, and that is much,
much easier than winning.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And they have the home field
advantage, right? Like, like, let's not
forget that. Uh, Gonk, thanks for the
thanks for the fiverr. I'm intimidated.
John looks pissed. Rightfully so.
>> I am, actually. I'm pissed about this.
>> World War totally unnecessary war of war
of choice. Oh, it I mean it's one of the
most boneheaded and we have a lot of
boneheaded wars. Um all of our wars are
boneheaded for the most part. Um World
War II not off the table. I'd say never.
Things can always spin out of control.
>> Yeah.
>> Um accident member for a month. Thank
you so much. Um is the only probable
reason Turkey hasn't been hit because of
NATO. If they're hit, it will trigger
Article 5.
>> That's a good question, too. Um,
that is that it could be it could be
that the Iranians,
you know, have more important things to
worry about right now than Turkey, but
sure that could be it. And and don't
don't forget Azarbaian,
right? There are Israeli there is an
Israeli base in Azarbaijan. The Israelis
have drones prepositioned there. the
Azarbaianis are or the Azeris are very
close to Turkey. So I wouldn't at all be
surprised to see this expand to
Azerbaian. Not at all.
>> Who's actually driving
10 Australian dollars from aluminus?
Thank you very much. Um
>> thank you.
>> Who's actually driving Iran policy in
this administration? Is there a coherent
inter agency process or are with I can
answer that significant autonomy outside
of normal national security council
channels?
>> That's a great question. It's a it's
quite an important question. In a normal
situation, there are two bodies called
the principal committee and the deputies
committee. The principal committee is
chaired by the president and it includes
the secretary of state, the secretary of
defense, the national security adviser,
the um chairman of the joint chiefs of
staff and the director of the CIA. The
deputies committee is the number twos
for all those people. It's chaired by
the vice president.
Um normally this policy would be coming
out of the the National Security
Council. In this odd scenario that we're
in right now, Marco Rubio is both
Secretary of State and National Security
Adviser.
And so this is Marco Rubio's policy.
We we learned from the the this leak
from the White House last week that JD
Vance was opposed to an attack on Iran.
Tulsi Gabbard was opposed to an attack
on Iran. And the chairman of the joints
came out and said that he was opposed to
an attack on Iran. Who does that leave?
Marco Rubio.
>> That's it. Marco Rubio is running this
policy.
>> Yeah. And BB Netanyahu. Um
>> BB Netanyahu. Yeah.
>> There's um a report coming out of
Jerusalem, John, that uh Israel is
claiming that um a Iranian strike killed
nine Israelis and injured 28.
Just
>> so so right before we started um we
started broadcasting, Robbie told us
that there were reports of an Iranian
hypersonic missile that had impacted a
bunker. Perhaps that's it.
>> Gotcha. Um let's uh
Archangel, thanks for the 499. How much
do you guys think this war will distract
from the Epstein stuff?
>> Yeah,
>> completely.
>> A lot.
>> We're not talking. Although I don't
think the EP people who care about
Epstein are going to forget and they're
well aware.
>> That's right.
>> Um
>> that's right.
>> Thanks for doing that.
>> But you know what though? One of the
things that this may do is distract
people from demanding that Pam Bondi
release the remaining 2.7 to three
million pages of documents.
>> That would be nice. Um Isaac, thanks for
the $5. The US consulate was attacked in
Pakistan yesterday. Yes,
>> I'm glad that came up. In response to
the attacks on Iran, have we started a
war with the Muslim world? Well, that's
what we did last time.
>> Yeah, the answer is probably yes. Yeah,
we that is that's exactly what we did
last time. We killed two million Muslims
from, you know, 2001 to 2020.
>> John, are we going to be
>> is this going to I mean, many Arab
countries have a huge division between
the politics of their street, as they
say it, and this, in other words, their
citizens and the policies of their
governments. Um, how much will this
could could a schism like blow up
someone's government? Um, and where
where would you think they would be?
>> Honestly,
>> if if I were, you know, the leader of
Bahrain, I would be genuinely worried
today. If I were the Pakistani
government, I would be genuinely worried
today. If I were
>> always be worried.
>> Yeah. But even an Indian leader, I would
be worried about what my population in
Kashmir would be doing right now.
>> Yeah, they're up. They're already
there's massive protests in Kashmir
because it's
>> Yeah, massive. And the Saudis, the Saudi
royal family, they've got to be on the
verge of cracking down in the eastern
province, which is almost entirely Shia
Muslim.
>> Um,
>> yeah, there there's a real risk today.
>> I'm glad you brought up the Saudis. So
it turns out there's heavy reporting I
know you've seen that uh the crown
prince um uh Ben Salman is uh he he was
a key adviser to Trump on all this and
his his council to Trump which obviously
Trump accepted was that a you the US
should and Israel should attack and b
there would never be a better time than
this um than now um
>> yeah you know the conventional wisdom
was that this is all Netanyahu all day
long and it turns out it wasn't
>> and and I think that that might be what
pushed Trump over the edge to make the
decision to actually attack that you
know you know that every time Netanyahu
flies to Washington he's going to say
please attack Iran please attack Iran
please attack Iran it's an entirely
different thing for the Israelis and the
Saudis to be on the same sheet of paper
I think that's what convinced Trump to
do
Got it. Uh Eskiny, thanks for thank you
for subscribing to deprogrammed uh 499
from uh keep it real. Since the war is
very unpopular to most Americans, uh
one, by the way, my my sub question
would be like, will it stay unpopular? I
would say you're going to see a bounce
the rally around the flag effect, but
starting at 21% is pretty bleak. Do you
think the do you think Israel will lose
support from the US and rely on India
more?
You know, I think that's the Trump plan
and I think that was the plan from the
first Trump administration. You remember
the the love fest that Trump and Modi
had in Texas when Modi came to the
United States to address um
Indian-Americans living in Texas? It was
a love fest and they had to have it in a
stadium to hold 50,000 people. So, I I
think that Trump and and I should add
this started with Bill Clinton. This is
not Donald Trump's idea, but I think
that the idea is to improve
ties to India to make relations between
the US and India as close as possible so
that we have an ally on that side of
Iran and we have a strong and populous
ally that can sort of offset some of the
bad juju that we have in the Middle
East.
Um, uh, Kitty von Meow, why do you think
Germany took in Netanyahu? Although
there's mixed reports about where where
Netanyahu really is, but there there
were several reports that he went to
Germany that I
>> Oh, looks like we lost Ted. Um, yeah,
you know, Netanyahu, every time the
Israelis want to bomb somebody,
Netanyahu runs away. So, the most of the
reports are that he's in Germany. I
heard a report this morning saying that
he's in Cyprus, which of course is that
much closer to Israel. Um,
and we're getting reports now that the
Israeli embassy in Abu Dhabi has been
hit, as well as an Emirati oil platform
uh in the Persian Gulf. We're going to
see a lot more of this, Ted. A lot more
of these uh these individual strikes,
targeted strikes. You know, let's
compare this to let's compare this to
say the 1990991
Gulf War
>> where you just like carpet bomb and just
just open the the bomb bays and let
bombs drop. This is a very smart
conflict. The targeting is
Oh, we are John. We are no long we don't
have you anymore.
Um, while we wait for him to come back,
I'm just going to just kind of share a
little bit of the information that I am
getting right now. It looks like the
John is right. The Israeli embassy in
Abu Dhabi was hit. Uh, also the Navy
base there has been hit. It is currently
burning. Uh, there are some oil
platforms have been hit and I'm seeing
reports that two ships trying to run the
streets of Hormuz have been hit.
So Iran's not playing.
>> Look around and find out.
>> I have not seen on these days.
>> I've not seen anything new about the
Abraham Lincoln. So that could be a
rumor. It could be real. I have no idea.
I'm seeing reports that Scott Ritter
says that the Lincoln was hit for
whatever that's worth. I don't know
where he's getting that from. If it's
true, it could just be. Trust me, bro.
Couldn't tell you.
>> All right. Thanks, Robbie.
>> Um,
>> yeah, we're gonna see a lot more of
this, Ted. a lot more.
>> How do you I mean, John, how do you how
do it, you know, a lot of things about
this blow my mind, but what
Oh my god, we just lost Robbie. I'll ask
>> I mean Yeah, Robbie's here. We just lost
John. John's coming kind of come back.
Um
h how do you deal This is a good
question for you anyway, Robbie.
>> Sure.
>> What do you make of the fact that Donald
Trump There's John.
>> Sorry. I don't know why. As soon as
Robbie got out, it threw me out again.
>> Oh, sorry about that. This is for both
of you guys. Anyway, uh why isn't Donald
Trump talking to the American people? I
mean, we're at war.
>> Caesar doesn't have to speak to the
American people. That's why
>> I I I I think I'm going to take a
slightly different attack. Um this is a
security measure. Uh I'm I'm going to
use kind of a strong word here. The
president is in hiding. That's what this
is. Just like George W. Bush for
security reasons went into hiding on
911.
Just in case all hell breaks loose, the
chances are very, very low. But just in
case all hell breaks loose, better to
protect the president now and have him
come out later. I think
>> I got to say I I strongly politically
disagree with that. Just um
strategically
>> politically. I do too. Yeah, agreed.
>> It's a [__] move. And like you're the
president of the [__] United States.
I mean, you know, we we read history.
Remember, we we know that like generals
used to go into battle with on at the
front at the front, right? Um, now they
hide now they hide at home in in you
know in their bunkers. What I mean to me
on 911 it was a very bad look for George
W. Bush to be nowhere to be found.
>> People are still talking about it 25
years later.
>> I don't know why Trump repeated that
mistake. I mean he studied what all of
Bush's mistakes. That's that was key to
his rise to power.
>> Here's where I disagree. For whatever
it's worth. When Trump started this war,
he did not bother ex making the case to
the American people. He didn't address
us. He didn't go on TV. He didn't send
out as much as a tweet.
He is arrogant to the extreme and he
thinks that he can do whatever he wants.
He does not care. I think it's peak ego
and that's why I mean seriously if if if
you are the imperator, why do you care
about what the pleb thinks? You don't.
I could be dead wrong. Y'all could be
right. That's that's a signal I'm
getting.
>> Robbie, I'm going to keep you on to talk
about this. I mean, look, we got to talk
about the War Powers Act, right? So, War
Powers Act passed after the at the end
of the Vietnam War. It was Congress's
attempt to reassert their war powers
that they had abandoned to numerous
presidents over the 200 years. Um, and
basically it requires the uh president
when he has a sustained commitment of
troops to go to Congress and get
congressional approval, right? Not a
declaration of war. Um it's war powers
act has been kind of like a problematic
you know kind of rule law ever since but
um looks are we going to get a vote
here? I mean it looks like we are going
to get a vote and if we do how's it
going to go?
>> You want me to answer
>> either one? Both.
>> Okay. I think that uh I think that there
are going to be war powers votes. Uh we
saw this morning on CNN reporting that
uh Mike Johnson is going to sort of be
forced to allowing a vote um on the War
Powers Act uh in the House. But my guess
is that Democrats are all going to vote
yes because they're just as big
warongers as the Republicans are.
>> Yeah, I agree. I mean, they're all paid
by the same people.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, if if if you're a fat pig and
you're going to the trough, are you
really going to go walk away from that?
No, we have the cheapest horish
government that money can buy.
>> Yeah. Yeah, we do. Thanks, Robbie.
>> Yeah, we do.
>> Um,
>> we do.
>> More uh499 from Perez. Thank you so
much. How ironic to rage a war based on
nukes and take out the leader who
withheld a religious ruling against
nukes.
>> Exactly right. You know, a a dear friend
of mine said yesterday that the next
Iranian Grand Ayatollah or or Supreme
Leader is just going to issue a new
Fatwa, revoking the old Fatwa and
calling for a nuclear uh uh weapons
program.
>> Yeah, it's of course they will. I mean,
you know, you and I have been talking
about this for a long time. Um okay. Uh
thanks for the 10 Australian dollars.
What's the current Israeli assessment?
Does Netanyahu's government actually
want a US invasion or do they prefer
Iran weakened with the regime intact as
a perpetual justification for their own
military posture?
>> You know, you know my answer to that.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. No, I think what the
Israelis want in Iran is what the
Israelis got in Libya. Chaos. They want
chaos. They want a civil war and they
want as many dead Iranians as they
possibly can get.
Yeah, agreed with that. Uh, let's see.
Could we Pittsburgh wants to know, could
we get more Sunday morning shows besides
emergency broadcasts?
>> You know, a a good friend of mine called
me uh day before yesterday and he says,
"Buddy." He says, "I'm going to tell you
something because I love you. You
haven't been in church in a year and you
should be ashamed of yourself. I want to
see you Sunday morning." I said, "Okay,
I I promise I'll be there. I'll be
there."
>> Yeah. It makes me I don't know about
Sunday morning shows.
>> Yeah. I mean, as it is, we're John and I
both work very hard. We have multiple
jobs and multiple gigs and
>> we do.
>> You know, we have to recharge. You know,
we Americans work too hard as it is. Um
I don't know. Maybe. I mean, I guess
there would be a world in which
anything's possible. Maybe we take
Monday off like restaurant workers or
something, right? Barbers.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Um why big
question. Why is the US Israel's [__]
If you could summarize, I would be
grateful. That's a it's a big good
question. I mean, we know it is.
>> Yeah. Because the the United States does
anything and everything the Israelis
tell it to do even when it's not in US
interests to do so.
>> Yeah. Um Yeah. So, I mean, why though is
the question.
>> And the the why is because of money and
politics. That's really what this comes
down to. You know, Citizens United made
it even worse. So, Miriam Adlesen could
donate $150 million to the RNC super PAC
and Apac can just spend people out of
office by challenging them in primaries
when they do the slightest thing that
the Israelis don't like.
>> Israel is there's also other things,
right? Israel is a is a tech hub and the
United States feels like um you know
that that alliance with the intel that
we get from you know from Israel is
considered valuable but also we're the
uh the Israel the Israelis lobby they're
spectacularly effective bullies. Uh they
smear everybody like you criticize
Israel you you know you're slimed as an
anti-semite. Um that's been their shtick
forever and up until very recently it
still worked. It's finally the, you
know, the spell is broken, but I mean,
there's more to it than that, but what
do you think, John?
>> Yeah, I think that's it. And and I think
I think this may be what breaks the
spell. If the Israelis suck us into a a
war, a longer term war, rather than just
a few days of bombing, we're in trouble,
and we're going to have to seriously as
a country reassess this relationship.
What do we get out of this relationship?
I understand exactly what the Israelis
get, but what do we get out of this
relationship?
>> By the way, producer Trent is reminding
uh me to mention to everybody who's on
YouTube that if you go to membership and
you become a tier 2 member, you will be
thanked by us in the closing credits um
of each and every show. So, please go
ahead and do that. He's in the middle of
updating that list. I just wanted to
remind you of that. Um, will the uh,
Bucktown crazy wants to know, will the
US need to escort commerce ships through
the straight of Hormuz?
>> Well, that's what Ronald Reagan did in
the 1980s when the Iranians threatened
to close the straight of Hormuz. He sent
the US Navy there to escort each and
every oil tanker through the straight. I
remember I remember being on a on a boat
in the Persian Gulf and seeing the the
SS Bridton. The Bridgton was famous in
the 80s because the Iranians attacked it
and set it ablaze. It it was the biggest
oil tanker in the world at the time. It
ended up being towed into port and
repaired. It took a couple of years to
repair it. But um we may be headed into
the same scenario where there's going to
have to be a long-term heavy US naval
presence in the Gulf just to escort uh
ships through the straight of Hormuz.
>> Um which of course could set us up for
being targeted. Then, you know, that's
it sets up it's a trigger for
escalation. Do we think this situation
will destroy the UAE's reputation and
cause a mass exodus as soon as the
airport reopens?
>> No.
>> It's the Vegas. It's the Vegas of uh
it's the Vegas of the Middle East. You
know,
>> honest to God, it's like paradise there.
>> They need it. They need it.
>> Um do you think Israel will be happy
with the US attacks on Iran so far? Do
you think they'll hold back moving
forward?
Thank you for all you do.
>> Uh yes and no. I think they are happy
because so much of the leadership has
been taken out. And you know, another
thing too, the Israelis killed more than
100 school girls in an attack on a on a
school in southern uh Iran. And people
talked about it for a couple of hours
and then just said, "Meh, no big deal.
It's a very big deal when you
deliberately target a school and murder
a hundred children. That's a very big
deal. But I think that they're thrilled
with the killing of Ayatollah Kamayi and
his entire family. His daughter, his
son-in-law, his grandson, they were all
killed in this attack. I think the
Israelis are thrilled with that. I think
the Israelis are very proud that um they
were able to take out literally the
entire Iranian military leadership. And
uh Ted, I I just missed that. Is the
French embassy under attack? Is that
what that said?
>> Um yeah, that's what Robbiey's saying.
The French base in Abu Dhabi has been
hit. Uh base, military base, not
embassy.
>> I see.
>> Um good
segue from Matthew. Why didn't Iran plan
better? I I had this question, too. Why
not have the senior commander safe
inside bunkers, which yesterday I
wrongly assumed would have been the
case? Same with the Ayatollah. Are the
Iranian military that incompetent?
>> No. The Ayatollah elected to not go to a
bunker because he said if there are no
bunkers for the Iranian people that he
will not go into a bunker. And to use
the the language from the Iranian uh
media today, um it said that uh that
that Ayatollah Kamayi drank from the
nectar of martyrdom and entered into
heaven.
>> I'm glad that you brought that up, John,
because like I talked I corresponded
with an Afghan friend. She's Shia and uh
and she said, "You guys don't understand
like for Shia what happened to Kamaya is
a win.
>> Every every Shia wants to be martyed
like this. We did them a favor." Yeah.
It's like thank you, you know, like it's
like winning a It's like winning a Nobel
Prize.
>> That's right. Go straight to heaven. If
when you're martyed, you go directly to
heaven without having to stop anywhere.
>> Mark's asking, um, there was reported
progress on a deal just before the
strikes happened. Do you think the
USIsraeli intent was always to nuke a
deal in favor of regime? That was the
Israeli intent, 1 million%.
>> Yes. And I think the and I think the
Americans didn't know how to negotiate
like the New York Times report said,
right? Like they basically kept changing
their demands. They were confusing as
hell. They had they were asking for
stuff the Iranians they knew the
Iranians couldn't agree to. This this I
think the Israelis were pulling the
strings here the entire time.
>> Agree completely. I can't even add
anything to that.
>> Um uh why wouldn't Iran make an an
incursion into Iraq? maybe take an oil
well or two would force the US to put
boots on the ground and play to Iran's
strength, especially since killing Kami
would motivate rural Iranians. And I
think there's a lot there, right? Like
um I Iran does have influence in Iraq.
We know that and you know they have
allied militias there. And they also,
you know, we should talk about like how
there has been a, you know, in Iran
there were some se reports, credible
supports of celebration, bigger supports
of mourning, but you know, obviously
it's like, well, what do the Iranians
think about all this? Well, it depends
who you ask, right? I mean, it's a it's
a diverse country of over 90 million
people. But, um, you know, my take when
I was in Iran was that the people in the
cities hate the government. They're
basically liberal. They don't they don't
want to, you know, they don't want to
wear the chador. They don't want to uh
you know, they they want to go drinking
and and and have a good time and go to
and and do be westerners. Um and then in
the rural areas, it's very different.
It's it's different. It's more
conservative and that's where the that's
the base of the government support.
>> I think that's exactly right.
>> I mean, it's the same divide that most
countries have, right? Rural are
>> including including the United States.
>> Totally. Um so, um yeah. So why would
they I mean I don't think Iran's in any
position to launch a ground incursion
into Iraq, but
>> no. And Iraq is a friendly country. Iran
and Iraq have very close relations.
They're they're both Shia Muslim
governments
>> and so there's no Iranian benefit.
>> That's why Salmani was over in Iraq when
he was killed.
>> That's right.
>> Um I think it does make I mean you know
one of the takeaways here is let's say
you're like North Korea and the US says
hey we want to talk. Why would you
believe anything we have to say? I mean,
we don't negotiate in good faith.
>> No, we don't.
>> Um, good morning to both of us. John,
unrelated, would like to know which of
your book would you suggest to read
overall when it comes to the CIA? And
which of your books would you say would
you suggest reading first?
>> Um, if if you can find one, I would say
first read um The Reluctant Spy, my
first book. And and I'm gonna I I think
I can reclaim the rights to that book
and publish a new edition. I'm I'm
looking into it now. Um, if you want to
learn more about CIA tactics, my second
book, uh, doing time like a spy and and
the second edition just came out, so
it's out there.
>> The Sha of Iran was impotent, says a
anonymous commentator. This Raza Palavi
is not his real son. I don't know. It
looks like him.
>> It looks just like him.
>> This is not a This is not a Ronin
Pharaoh situation.
>> No. Um, and he's just as [__] dumb,
too.
>> Yes. And then there's that.
>> So, I mean, by the way, I mean, what I
mean, isn't it [__] embarrassing to
see so many like my carto fellow
cartoonists on the right and journalists
saying like, "Oh, you know, we're going
to reinstall the shaft.
Let's make Iran Persia again." And
>> it's like, it's just I mean, he's the
he's Akmed Chalabi all over again.
>> Yeah, he is. except not as intelligent.
>> How embarrassing.
>> Um, not relevant to recent events, but I
was curious if you two had a reading
list of several books you found
eliminating to reach your great
understanding of modern foreign policy
and history.
>> Oh, wow. You know, early on the the one
I started with was uh The Rise and Fall
of the CIA. M
>> uh it was written in the 1980s
and um and it was my first real like
deep
>> introduction to CIA uh covert action
operations and covert operational
failures. Um from the creation of the
CIA until Iran Contra.
If you can find it, I'd say start with
that. And anything that Timothy Weiner
writes,
>> you're going to want to check it out.
Uh, I'm I'm a huge fan of Robert Fisk's
The Great War between civilizations, um,
as like sort of a one-stop shopping for
people who want to know about Western
policy in the Middle East. Um, anyway,
um, not well verssed to these things.
Gabby says, "What are the chances that
Iran or another country actually attacks
American soil?"
>> Very zero.
>> Very small.
>> Yeah.
>> Very, very small. Um, okay. So, more
questions. Uh
um
wait, hold on. I'm I'm trying to bring
this up. Okay, John, have you read Carl
Young? Toby wants to know. And thanks
for the three Australian dollars.
Yeah, I have read Carl Young because I
very briefly dated a a girl who was a
Yungian and um yeah, learned a lot. Not
sure I agreed with everything, but yeah,
interesting stuff. And I'll tell you
what, it's good for dinner conversation.
>> Uh managing next next dinner we have. I
will I will uh hold you to that, John.
Uh managing things. Thanks for the 10
bucks. Is there any line that the BBI
Israeli government could cross that
would cause the US government to stop
the blank checks? I'd say going nuclear.
>> Yeah, I agree with that. You took the
words right out of my mouth.
>> Uh let's uh let's see what if Thanks for
the uh Nasir. Thanks for the 499. I wish
George Carlin were were still alive.
Boy, would he have a field day now.
Alive anyway.
>> So true.
>> Um, Jacob, thanks for the 999. Is it
likely, John, that the CIA's
paramilitary is on the ground in Iran
already?
>> That's a great question.
>> That's a great question. I would say
probably not. Now, granted, my my
information is dated, but
to have the CIA paramilitary on the
ground to carry out targeted killings,
the president would have to um assert
that a person is uh a what's called a
clear and present danger to the United
States, to an American installation,
um and to or to an American person.
And I I don't think we're there.
>> Okay. Um, thank you very much to both
Sean B and Kangorski for becoming uh
members. Um, let's see. Uh, Papadupos,
thanks for the six. Hey John, do you
think Greece might get attacked as well?
And if they do, do you think they have
enough military strength to handle it?
>> You know what? A friend of mine in the
US military mentioned this to me
yesterday. He said, "We really need to
be worried about Suda Bay in Cree. Uh
there's an enormous American naval
presence there. Um it's where it's where
the USS Gerald Ford is, you know, just
offshore because it's the nearest major
port that can accommodate a US aircraft
carrier. So the answer is yes. I think
we should be a little worried about
this.
>> Um al and uh another comment um thanks
for the five Australian dollars from
aluminus. Uh but why? How does Israel
benefit from absolute chaos like in
Libya and Iraq? What's the end goal? How
can this lead to lasting security for
them? You know what? I don't think it
can lead to lasting security. I think
this is the fallacy in in Israeli
policy. The Israeli view is if there's
chaos, they won't have the wherewithal
to work on a bomb. And if they don't
have the wherewithal to work on a bomb,
then Israel is going to be safe for
another month or 6 months or one year or
whatever it is. And so if you just keep
the region in a state of chaos, you can
protect yourself with nuclear weapons
and those other states because they're
in chaos can't develop a a legitimate
weapon again to use against you.
It's a short-term view, not a long-term
view.
Yeah, I think I think one fallacy
especially when people on the left are
analyzing like western and US and
Israeli policy is that we kind of assume
that the actions are based on some kind
of logic that is even right for the
people who are perpetrating it. Um it
may be that they're engaged in something
that's self-destructive and they're just
making a mistake. You know, I mean the
march of folly, right? I mean and I
think I mean I think that's what is
going on. I mean, you and I have talked
about I mean, why on earth would Israel
have wanted to overthrow Assad and have
an ISIS regime right on their [__]
border? That doesn't seem good for
Israeli internal security, but yet they
did it.
>> The the Syrian government yesterday
endorsed announced its support for the
USIsraeli attack on Iran. I felt like I
was in the Twilight Zone.
>> That's so crazy. This is a guy who was
this guy was uh you know in al Qaeda.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He was the number two in
ISIS.
>> That's crazy. Yeah. I mean I look I
think I think what's you know the look
the thing is um Stratfor who are not
always right but they're right about
some things. Uh they say that the U that
US foreign policy is based on disruption
of possibly emerging regional
superpowers. Right. Just just keep
everyone else off guard. that's your
thing. You [__] them up. You throw a
push a stick into their their bicycle
spokes. The Israelis are just the same
thing on acid. That that's what this is
about. They're just trying to, you know,
instead of just like the Chinese
approach is very different. The Chinese
approach is like we can all make money
together. Um, you know, let's just peace
is war is bad, peace is more profitable,
peace is smarter. But that's not the
USIsraeli model.
>> Agreed.
Um,
let's see. Uh, why, uh, uh, Joe
Readingen wants to know, "Why are there
still British base bra bases, sorry,
braces in Cyprus? Will there be added
pressure to remove them now? Get your
Brits out."
>> I sure hope so. Hey, Robbie is telling
us that SenCom is announcing that three
American soldiers have been killed
>> in some kind of an attack.
>> Let's see. Um,
yeah, I'm seeing this. Uh, they're not
there's not really any details here. Um,
several other people also several other
soldiers were injured.
>> Does it say where?
>> Um,
in action is all it says. We're
withhold. They're withholding additional
information including their identities
until 24 hours after next of kin have
been notified.
>> Oh boy.
Yeah,
>> it was inevitable.
>> It was inevitable.
Um, yeah, people keep asking about the
sleeper cells. I got we got to
reiterate, there's probably no sleeper
cells. Um,
>> no. And if they are, they're in places
that don't have very many Americans. The
the when I think of Iranian sleeper
cells, I think of Pakistan because when
I was living in Pakistan, there
absolutely were Iranian sleeper cells
and they were doing bad [__]
Um, otaku, thanks for the 10 bucks. Um,
do we think Huckabe is another
individual who became an interloper
after being in Israel for so long and
sees himself as an Israeli more than as
an American? Oh, I think before he got
to Israel, he saw himself as more
Israeli than American. This guy's This
guy is actually dangerous to US foreign
policy. He needs to be removed. Anybody
who would fet the traitor Jonathan Pard
in the American embassy like some kind
of [__] hero needs to be removed from
office. He's doing damage to our
country.
Uh couldn't agree more. Um and and by
the way, um thanks managing things for
the dollar. Outside of Israel, which
regimes in the Middle East are happy
with the removal of the Sha/Islamic
Republic? Well, that's different. Um
let's say say the Islamic Republic.
>> Yeah, the Islamic Republic. Uh every one
of the Gulf countries,
>> every single one of them, Saudi Arabia,
Kuwait, Bahrain, Gutter, Oman, and the
United Arab Emirates. Thrilled
>> from way
>> I'm sorry. Let me finish real quickly.
You can add to that. Jordan, Egypt, and
apparently now Syria.
>> Weird. Uh way I see it, thanks for the
generous two $10 donations. Much
appreciated.
>> Thank you.
>> Um let's see. Oh, and um Jay, support
from Utah. You guys heard about the
former Iranian president being confirmed
to be dead, right? That's Akmad.
>> Yeah, they killed Ahmedad yesterday.
>> Uh inexplicably. And apparently they
wiped out his entire family as well.
>> And there was another Who was the other
one that they attacked?
>> They said he was a reformer. That's not
true.
>> Whoa. Who was the the other the other uh
former president that they attacked?
>> That's it. Ahmed.
>> It was just Ahmed Nad. Okay.
Um, if the intelligence Illuminous
Katar, thanks for the five Australian
dollars. If the intern intelligence
community thinks that the current
administration is making Iran decisions
based outside of the US national
interest assessments, why aren't they
trying to solve that, John?
>> Well, it's because at the end of the
day,
these agencies and departments have to
do what the president tells them to do.
And if this is the president's policy,
they are compelled to carry out the
president's policy. Keep in mind, my
favorite quote from former Egyptian
president uh Gamala Abdaser, the thing
about you Americans is you never make
clear-cut stupid decisions. You only
make complicated stupid decisions, which
makes us wonder if there is something to
them which we are missing.
>> That's so [__] awesome. That's so
great. And the US Army is now announcing
that it sank an American ship. I'm
sorry, an Armenia uh an Iranian ship.
Forgive me. The US Army is saying that
it sank an Iranian ship.
>> Well, Trump had threatened at the
beginning of this war uh a couple of
days ago that he was going to destroy
the Iranian Navy.
>> Yeah, there's not much to the Iranian
Navy. They've got a sub or two. They've
got a couple of ships. It's not going to
be
>> got
a lot of patrol boats.
>> Lot of patrol boats. and they're mostly
IRGC
>> uh ZC carianis
thanks for the 29 um and uh donation
much appreciated um yeah so um John uh
we are we're in we're an hour in I can
keep going but it's what do you think
>> let's answer our questions
>> okay let's answer our questions indeed
um okay so
uh
um complicated stupid action is so
great. Uh, thanks for the 999 from Keep
It Real. Have you heard the conspiracy
about how Israeli tourists burned down
part of Patagonia's forest, Argentina?
And before the fires occurred, the
president of Argentina changed the law
allowing foreigners to buy land in
Argentina. I new to New to me. I hadn't
heard that.
>> Yeah, don't know. And now AP is
reporting that three service members
killed and five seriously wounded.
>> But not where or how.
>> No, not where?
>> Weird. Okay. Um
uh can you Oh, this is good. Trevor
House, can you guys simply explain why
you are so against the attack? Do you
agree that Iran is extremely dangerous
when left alone in a perfect world? What
do you think America's stance should be
on Iran? I'm really glad for this
question. John, why don't you take it?
>> Uh, Iran
posed no threat to the United States.
None.
None. It had no nuclear weapon. It had
no nuclear weapons program. That was
confirmed twice by the CIA and by the
International Atomic Energy Agency
>> and don't and didn't want one
>> and didn't want one. and there was a
fatwa against developing one. And even
if they had one, they didn't have a
delivery system to to deliver it. So, um
you know, why are we doing Israel's
dirty work for it? If the Israelis
wanted to attack Iran, then go ahead,
attack Iran, but why did we have to do
it? Why are Americans dying in the name
of Israeli foreign policy?
>> Would you agree with the assumption that
Iran was quote unquote dangerous? I mean
the the brief against Iran has been that
it's a promoter of terrorist groups like
Hamas and Hzbollah and the Houthis in
Yemen and that they basically are an
exporter and destabilizing force
throughout the Middle East. Do you agree
with that?
>> Um no I believe that
terrorism is in the eye of the beholder.
There are I mean Hezbala certainly is a
terrorist group or has been a terrorist
group in the past. It blew up the
American embassy twice. It blew up the
Marine Corps barracks in Beirut, killed
hundreds and hundreds of Americans,
including several of my CIA colleagues
decades ago. It is now a legitimate
political entity in in uh Lebanon. It's
a major parliamentary force. Um, with
the exception of targeting civilians on
October 7th, I think that that Hamas was
created to liberate the Palestinian
people from Israeli oppression. And so
often times terrorism is in the eye of
the beholder. I would say that that the
Iranians were responding
with their support for these groups to
what they saw as Israeli terrorism
against Palestinians and more broadly
against Iran.
>> Yeah. Let's not forget, right? Like when
the re I mean let's take go back in the
way back when machine to 1979
um they overthrow the repressive sha of
Iran whose son they'd like to now
install who was presiding over a
despotic tyrannical regime with a
torture regime that is crazy under this
horrible Sabak organization. Um 1980
uh Iran uh Iraq supported and armed and
financed and encouraged by the United
States attacks Iran. They end up having
to fight this brutal war that we never
paid attention to or even covered in the
American media. The Iran Iraq war from
1980 to 1986 if memory serves
>> 80 88 89 something like that. And then
when and then like out of all that we
basically um you know the the Iranians
basically never got a start. We imposed
these hor these brutal sanctions against
their economy for the entire time. I
mean they've been on defense. I mean I
mean I think the brief in favor of Iran
is that they're also like a regionally
po um
nonuno unopolar force in that region.
Right. It's kind of like US and Israeli
dominance would be complete if not for
Iran. Um Iran is the counterwe
counterbalance. I would argue that
counterbalances are useful and more
stabilizing than having um you know he
hegemonic control by one power in a
region. I mean, so I mean, but like you,
John, I mean, it's basically it's like
who who the Iranians want to have govern
them is not our [__] business because
we're not. It's their [__] country.
If they want to overthrow it, they can.
If they want, they have in the past.
They know how.
>> And uh we c and if even if we want to,
we can't get the new government that we
want. We'll just end up breaking things,
which is what we're doing. Um we are bad
at this. I mean, point to one example of
the United States, you know, you bombing
a country into regime change and having
it work out well. Um, it's killing
people for no end. What destroying
infrastructure towards no end,
>> we could we could have had a peaceful
economic and diplomatic relationship
with these people decades ago. If we
wanted it, all we had to do is pick up
the phone.
>> That's it. That's true. That's true.
So yeah, that that's it's all right.
Sorry, I get a little bit heated here.
Um, okay. Um,
uh, John Swiss J says, John says that
Iran has a couple of hypersonic
missiles, but open source intel and
other intelligence assessments is that
they have a few thousand.
>> Oh, if that's true, I stand corrected.
It was my understanding that they had
about a half a dozen that they got from
the Russians.
Darkness is saying questioning me. Iran
is useful and stabilizing. I mean, it's
not a bad it's not a good thing to have
one. Look at what the whole 1991, you
know, after the collapse of the Soviet
Union and the US and the world became a
unipolar environment for a while until
the Chinese and the Russians got their
[__] together. Um, it was not a good
place. I mean, you know, we drove the
car and we drove it into a ditch
repeatedly. I don't know. That's my
take. Um,
you know, it's but again, basically,
it's not our business. Um, Illuminous
Cat, thanks for the five. Um, Israel
isn't a monolith. It's allowed to have a
propaganda. It's been allowed to have a
propaganda and lobby network in the
West, to say the least. Does the West
benefit from uh absolute chaos in the
Middle East?
>> Absolutely not.
>> Absolutely not. We benefit from
stability in the Middle East.
>> 100%. Couldn't agree more. Um, okay. Let
me see like what qu um
people, I just want to say, can we just
all get along? Can we just get along?
Can we stop taking making it horrible
for the older people and the kids? Of
course, we all know that Rodney King
quote. It's pretty funny, though. It
shouldn't be funny, but you know, you
have to sort of ruthfully laugh. Um,
thank you very much Martin C. Hugh to
joining deprogrammed. Um,
and I think we are basically at the end
of our questions. Um, I'm really
>> good
>> sorry for all the people whose questions
we didn't get to. Um, please bear with
us. There were more listeners and
viewers than we're used to. Um, and so
>> but thanks for joining us.
>> Definitely very much so. So, we are here
on Drogram. If you're, you know, some of
you are new to the show, we do this
every Monday through Friday at 9:00 am
Eastern time and uh we try to answer as
many questions as possible. We're a
fastmoving show. We appreciate your uh
your likes, your follows, your
subscribes, and of course your
donations. Um please uh tune in
tomorrow, Monday, 9:00 am Eastern time.
John, have a good remaining time in New
York
>> and hope everything goes well and we
will
>> great
>> talk to you guys later. Bye
>> bye everybody.